IBT Political and Legislative Action Department, 1960-1961 IBT0077
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Political and Legislative Action Department
1960-1961
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0077
1.5 Linear Feet Correspondence and scripts re "A Bench in the Park", a film about the Landrum-Griffin Act sponsored by the IBT
Series 1 of this collection houses the scripts, correspondence, and production files relating to the IBT sponsored film A Bench in the Park. Legislative and Political Action Dept. head Sid Zagri headed up this project on the Teamsters side. Series 2 of this collection houses miscellaneous materials from the IBT Political and Legislative Action Department as well as the legislative and Political Education Department.
Arrangement
Collection: Political and Legislative Action Department Records Organized into two series: Sid Zagri Files- A Bench in the Park Files and Political and Legislative Action Department Files.
Series: Arranged document type (correspondence, scripts)
Biographical / Historical
According to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters website, "The Department of Political and Legislative Action mobilizes Teamster members and affiliates around campaigns for national contracts, federal and state legislative campaigns, and federal, state and local political campaigns. The department accomplishes this by energizing Teamster members to take direct action, as well as helping Teamster affiliates build their own member mobilization infrastructure. Field Representatives live and work in all regions of the United States, raising DRIVE money, electing Teamster candidates, educating Teamster members and building our political program."
"A Bench in the Park" was a 30-minute film sponsored by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters regarding the Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959, also known as the Landrum-Griffin Act. It is a dramatization of the potential effects of the law on union activities. It also cover the turning points in American labor history. It was produced in 1960. The screenplay was written by Doris Gilbert. It was produced by Martine Lancer and directed by Anton Leader. It's purpose was to be shown at union halls and on television.
Scope and Contents
Series 1 consists of documentation regarding the writing of "A Bench in the Park", a Teamsters sponsored 30 minute film on the potential effects of the Landrum Griffin Act (1959) on union activities. The documentation includes correspondence between Sid Zagri, director of the IBT Legislative and Political Affairs Department and the project's various players including the screenwriter, producer and director and IBT officers, namely James R. Hoffa, Harold Gibbons and John English.
Series 2 contains miscellaneous files from the Department, including files that were not published by the Department but were used by ther Department.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred from the IBT.
General
Labor unions; Labor
- Sid Zagri Files - A Bench in the Park and other files, 1960-1968; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of documentation regarding the writing of "A Bench in the Park", a Teamsters sponsored 30 minute film on the potential effects of the Landrum Griffin Act (1959) on union activities, as well as transcripts of testimony provided by Sid Zagri before Congress. The film documentation includes correspondence between Zagri, director of the IBT Legislative and Political Affairs Department and the project's various players including the screenwriter, producer and director and IBT officers, namely James R. Hoffa, Harold Gibbons and John English.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by document type.
  - "A Bench in the Park" Correspondence, January 1960-August 1961; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Bench in the Park" Miscellaneous, 1960; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "A Bench in the Park" Summary of Production, 1960; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "A Bench in the Park" Treatment, 1960; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "A Bench in the Park" Script, First Draft, 1960; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "A Bench in the Park" Script, Second Draft, 1960; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "A Bench in the Park" Script, Final Draft, 1960; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Statement before the Judiciary Committee on S. 2813 by Sidney Zagri, 1962 April 6; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Statement before Select Subcommittee on Labor by Sidney Zagri on H.R. 77, May 26, 1965; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Political and Legislative Action Department Files, 1968-2008; Series 2
  This series is arranged chronologically. Undated files appear last.
  This series contains general fils having to do with the Political and Legislative Action Department / Legislative and Political Education Department.
  - Congressional and Legislative Facts, 90th Congress, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Congressional and Legislative Facts, 95th Congress, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A Handbook of Great Labor Quotations Booklet, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Labor Unions: Champions of Social Justice Thesis by Gregory George Guthrie, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Teamsters for Kerry Materials, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alliance for Economic Justice Gephardt for President Campaign Materials, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Teamsters for Obama Campaign Materials, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Reports, 99th Congress, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Status Sheet on Bills Pending Before the 102nd Congress, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Picture of Teamster Truck in Front of Missouri State Capitol, IBT0077 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 16)
  - 90th Congress - Legislative Fact Book, 1967; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Legislative Priorities, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - DRIVE Power, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Hoffa's Impact on Real Wages, 1964; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Teamsters with information concerning three candidates for the 1968 Presidency: Nixon, Humphrey, and Wallace, 1968 October 18; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - March on for Voting Rights, 2021 August; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Political Smokescreen Over Civil Rights, Circa 1963; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)